import { QuizQuestionList } from "../typings/quizTypes";

const CH_NUM = 2;

const questions: QuizQuestionList = [
  {
    question:
      "Which of the following elements is NOT one of the six that make up 98% of most organisms' body weight?",
    options: ["hydrogen", "nitrogen", "carbon", "iron"],
    correctIndex: 3,
    chapter: CH_NUM,
  },
  {
    question: "All atoms of a certain element have the same number of protons.",
    options: ["True", "False"],
    correctIndex: 0,
    chapter: CH_NUM,
  },
  {
    question:
      "All matter is composed of certain basic substances called elements.",
    options: ["True", "False"],
    correctIndex: 0,
    chapter: CH_NUM,
  },
  {
    question:
      "The three isotopes of carbon 12C, 13C and 14C have different numbers of _______?",
    options: ["electrons", "protons", "neutrons"],
    correctIndex: 2,
    chapter: CH_NUM,
  },
  {
    question: "Protons have a __________ electrical charge.",
    options: ["positive", "negative", "neutral"],
    correctIndex: 0,
    chapter: CH_NUM,
  },
  {
    question: "Electrons always have the same amount of potential energy.",
    options: ["True", "False"],
    correctIndex: 1,
    chapter: CH_NUM,
  },
  {
    question: "The atomic number of an atom is the same as __________.",
    options: [
      "the atom's mass",
      "the number of protons the atom has",
      "the number of neutrons the atom has",
    ],
    correctIndex: 1,
    chapter: CH_NUM,
  },
  {
    question:
      "If an atom has an atomic number of 17 and an atomic mass of 35, the number of neutrons in its nucleus equals _____.",
    options: ["17", "18", "35", "52"],
    correctIndex: 1,
    chapter: CH_NUM,
  },
  {
    question:
      "If an atom with an atomic number of 9 and an atomic mass of 19 is electrically neutral, it has __________ electrons.",
    options: ["9", "10", "19", "28"],
    correctIndex: 0,
    chapter: CH_NUM,
  },
  {
    question: "Radioactive isotopes are used to __________.",
    options: [
      "determine the age of fossils",
      "trace chemicals during biochemical reactions",
      "detect thyroid abnormalities",
      "all of the above",
    ],
    correctIndex: 3,
    chapter: CH_NUM,
  },
  {
    question:
      "Electrons that are farther from the nucleus have more potential energy than electrons closer to the nucleus.",
    options: ["True", "False"],
    correctIndex: 0,
    chapter: CH_NUM,
  },
  {
    question:
      "The subatomic particle with an atomic mass of one and a neutral charge is a(n) __________.",
    options: ["proton", "neutron", "electron"],
    correctIndex: 1,
    chapter: CH_NUM,
  },
  {
    question: "The nucleus contains ________.",
    options: ["protons", "neutrons", "electrons", "protons and neutrons"],
    correctIndex: 3,
    chapter: CH_NUM,
  },
  {
    question:
      "Electron shells, other than the first one, can contain up to eight electrons.",
    options: ["True", "False"],
    correctIndex: 0,
    chapter: CH_NUM,
  },
  {
    question:
      "An electrically neutral atom with an atomic number of 7 will have _____ electron shell(s).",
    options: ["1", "2", "3", "4"],
    correctIndex: 1,
    chapter: CH_NUM,
  },
  {
    question:
      "Electrically neutral magnesium (atomic number 12) is an example of an inert (non reactive) atom.",
    options: ["True", "False"],
    correctIndex: 1,
    chapter: CH_NUM,
  },
  {
    question: "Which of the following is an inert (non-reactive) atom?",
    options: [
      "hydrogen; atomic number = 1",
      "oxygen; atomic number = 8",
      "neon; atomic number = 10",
      "chlorine; atomic number = 17",
    ],
    correctIndex: 2,
    chapter: CH_NUM,
  },
  {
    question: "The sodium ion (Na+) has 12 protons (atomic number of Na = 11).",
    options: ["True", "False"],
    correctIndex: 1,
    chapter: CH_NUM,
  },
  {
    question: "Which bond is most easily broken?",
    options: ["triple covalent", "hydrogen", "phosphodiester", "glycosidic"],
    correctIndex: 1,
    chapter: CH_NUM,
  },
  {
    question: "What type of bond is formed when atoms share electrons?",
    options: ["ionic", "covalent", "hydrogen"],
    correctIndex: 1,
    chapter: CH_NUM,
  },
  {
    question:
      "Chlorine (atomic number = 17) needs _____ electron(s) to fill its outermost electron shell.",
    options: ["0", "1", "7", "8"],
    correctIndex: 1,
    chapter: CH_NUM,
  },
];

export default questions;
